In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled by some transcendental entity or law?
Is it like the hand of God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no control, even over his own will.
I don't want to live
like this, buried in his dream...
You and Griffith...
I hope it works out between you and Griffith.
Hey.
Judeau, Corkus...
Come on, we need to talk.
Griffith!
He would be able to stop him!
Feel no shame about shape
Weather changes their phrase
Even mother will show you another way
So put your glasses on
Nothing will be wrong
There's no blame. There's no fame
It's up to you
The first words should be found
Whatever holds you back
I...
...can...
I can get it off
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Don't know why you're afraid
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late
Separation
What is this all of a sudden?
It's not sudden.
I've been thinking about this since
before we set off for our last battle.
Are you discontent about something?
Of course I'm not...
Not at all.
During these past three years....
...I've really enjoyed myself.
It's been like one great party.
How could I be discontent?
Oh, I didn't ask your name yet...
Then why do you...
Corkus, come on.
Shut up!
I am Sir Corkus, commander
of one of our companies!
What's wrong with me going
to a bar and hitting on a girl or two?
We've got free rein in any pub in Windham...
...once they recognize us as
Band of the Hawk commanders!
In the street, we're mobbed
by kids and women as we walk by!
Of course!
We are the heroes who saved this kingdom!
Soon, we'll be admitted
into society as nobles!
We'll be able to settle down in the court!
With luck, we could become
lords of our own castles!
All of this would be impossible
under ordinary circumstances!
Right?
But we finally got our hands on it!
And it took a lot of blood,
sweat, and tears too!
And now you say you're
ready to throw it all away...
In any case...
Since killing people is your only talent...
...dancing at parties with
the ladies is probably beyond you!
What you say is true.
I can't do anything but wield a sword.
The first time I killed a man, I was
just a kid without a clue in the world.
I've never known anything but the battlefield.
I never tried to know more.
Killing others to survive...
That's all I've ever done.
But...
I could have been
content living that way...
If just one person...
Never mind who...
If only someone had
ever cared about me...
But...
After wandering from one battlefield
to another, it finally hit me...
When it's kill or be killed, it doesn't
mean shit if someone cares or not.
Yearning for that is just childish.
Even so...
I ended up meeting him...
The one person
I desperately wanted to notice me.
He had nothing whatsoever in his possession.
And he was driven
to obtain everything.
But because he aspires
to such great heights...
...his skills always have
to be honed to perfection.
And so he can't afford
to surround himself with the weak.
But the funny thing is
the more I see him in that light...
...the more dazzling he seems to me.
I've had enough of it. Being part of
his dream, always looking up at him.
I want to achieve a goal of my own,
so that I can call myself his equal.
He's the one man I can't
have looking down on me.
Call yourself Griffith's equal, huh?
Cut the crap!
That's what you call childish bullshit!
He's special, don't you see?
He's not like the rest of us!
You have no talent but slaying people...
Yet here you are, way out of your
class, as our raider commander...
And you have no one
to thank for that but Griffith!
I have no interest in rank or position.
It's something else that I'm after...
Something I have
to claim with my own hands.
That's what I mean by childish drivel!
Something you have
to claim with your own hands?
Life would be a lot easier
if we could all find such a thing!
Listen!
We all have to make compromises
in life, depending on our limitations...
...and the cards that
we're dealt in this world!
People who think
that all they need is a dream...
You guys make me sick!
That's nothing but an excuse
for cowards who can't face reality!
Corkus...
What about you?
Isn't there something
you want to claim too?
Gimme a break!
I need to get some sleep!
I can't tolerate this
immature fool any longer!
That Corkus... He may not look it, but
he was once a band of thieves' leader.
I suppose at one point, he did have
something that he wanted to claim...
...with his own hands, like you.
As for myself...
I've always been proficient
at anything I set my mind to.
My quick wit and skills with a knife
have always been superior to most.
But I could never be
the best at any one thing.
That's why I decided...
If I couldn't be the best...
...then I would serve
under someone who could.
I think everyone has
the desire to attain something...
I'll see you out...
I hope you find it...
That something you're after...
Hey, Guts...
Yeah?
Why don't you ask Casca to go with you?
What?
What are you talking about?
As if it wasn't obvious enough
already. Griffith's the one she...
I don't think Casca can ever be with Griffith.
Why?
Because there's only one
thing that Griffith is after...
And winning Princess Charlotte's
hand is the fastest shortcut to it.
And it's the only way he can ever hope to.
Anyway, what do you think of Casca?
Sure, I think Casca's attractive.
There aren't a lot of women you can
trust your back to on the battlefield.
But I don't really see Casca as a woman...
She's more like my comrade-in-arms.
Well, then...
No...
...you're wrong.
She only has eyes for Griffith.
So for now, I can't be the one for her.
I see.
I guess I was the only one who
thought there was some hope for you.
Thanks for coming along.
I'll be off now...
Guts!
You...
You're so mean. How could
you leave without saying anything?
Why? Are you tired
of the Band of the Hawk?
Rickert...
Are you leaving?
Yeah...
Are you resigning from
the Band of the Hawk?
Sorry...
You're sorry?
That doesn't explain anything!
You've got to tell us why!
The Band of the Hawk is like
your own family! Isn't that true?
Stop it, Rickert.
Why...
It's a man's decision.
We should just let him go.
But Guts is the commander of the Raiders!
He's crucial to the Band of the Hawk!
We were already invincible before he joined.
But...
Shut up!
Hey, I'm going to tell you this now!
I've always hated you!
I'll never acknowledge your skills!
You're not special at all!
And you'll never be like Griffith!
If we ever meet on the battlefield someday...
...you'd better watch your back!
Guts...
Thanks for everything...
I told you this long ago...
You belong to me.
I claimed you with this sword of mine.
When to go into battle,
when to die... that is all up to me.
If you want to free
yourself from my control...
...then just as you did before...
Wrest yourself away with your blade!
Griffith!
You can't just let me go
with a smile and "goodbye," huh?
I see.
Wait!
Are you two serious?
You're going to cross swords
even though you're comrades?
Stay back, Casca!
Get out of the way.
What are you saying?
If you two fight with real swords,
you won't escape unharmed!
Hands off! What are you doing?
There's no way around it,
under these circumstances...
What are you all doing?
We've got to stop them!
They'll kill each other!
This is between the two of them.
It's not our place to interfere.
But we can't just...
Have you gotten so used to
the genteel life that you've forgotten?
We must settle things by our swords.
This is our way as mercenaries, isn't it?
But...
She's changed...
She's never hesitated before
under Griffith's orders...
...even if her comrades
were in mortal danger.
Does she realize it herself?
That she's starting to change?
His eyes look as if he's glaring at an enemy.
But...
...even if he hates me
or if he considers me a traitor...
I'm still going!
It's just as it was three years ago...
It all began with a sword fight...
and it will end with a sword fight.
I'm proud that I've come this far...
The fact you're challenging me
now shows I'm valuable enough...
...for you to shed blood for.
He's become immeasurably strong...
But...
Griffith can definitely stop him!
That's right. Then everything will
be the same as it was before...
Is that my wish?
Is it my wish that...
...Guts stays with me?
He makes no attempt
to display his will to fight.
However, he is completely on guard...
...and his eyes are resolute.
Do you really wish so much...
...to be free of my control?
No, I won't allow it!
My best chance is in the first strike...
I've got to deflect his sword
as soon as he swings downward.
Then I'll strike his shoulder!
If my sword strays the least bit off
the mark, I could end up killing him.
Nevertheless, if I can't make him mine...
I don't care!
Now!
Griffith!
Goodbye.
Griffith...
Guts!
Guts is gone.
He didn't even look back.
That was a fluke!
That was definitely a fluke!
I'll never admit that he won!
You're going to be all right...
It's like you just stumbled
over a stone in the street.
It's not a big deal at all...
The place you're headed...
It's far beyond this, right?
You'll be fine...
You'll get back on your feet...
...and start walking again...
before you know it.
No, the snow is melting...
Please go to bed quickly,
otherwise you will get sick, my lady.
Fine, I shall retire now.
You may leave now.
Then good night, my lady.
Sir Griffith!
Sir Griffith, what happened to you?
It's such a rainy night!
Good evening, Princess Charlotte.
May I be so bold as to request
entry into your chambers?
What?
If someone saw us like this,
it might stain your honor, Princess.
Y-Yes...
Come in...
Thank you.
Please excuse my rudeness,
visiting a lady's bedroom...
...at such a late hour
and soaking the place with rain.
I missed you so much.
Ever since you were sent to the battlefield...
...I have constantly been afraid
that I would hear of your death.
Even after you returned, so many
terrifying and tragic things occurred!
Why... Why didn't you
come to see me earlier?
No...
Griffith...
Griffith!
Are you scared?
Stop it...
Your fear and sorrow... Throw
everything into the fire and let it burn...
Goodbye...
Griffith?
Well, well, who should it be
but the next White Hawk general!
To think that Your Excellency, of
all people, should be here at this time.
That's right. My sword was...
I will hear your story later, at my leisure.
Haul him off!
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight. You're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying your crown?
I'm spending my glass, walking back.
So wear my glass. You're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...